Nolan Henry

mr.nolanhenry@gmail.com (757) 288-5312 Washington, DC 20007

GitHub: https://github.com/enfenry

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/nolanhenry

Portfolio: https://enfenry.github.io

Full Stack Web Developer with a passion for finding creative solutions to complex problems. Well-versed in providing pricing analyses and cost proposals in support of government contracts. Experienced in process improvement through programming and developing user-friendly interfaces. Enjoy both collaborative environments where knowledge can be shared and independent ones where self-learning and a strong initiative are rewarded.

SKILLS

Technical

Adobe After Effects | Adobe Premiere Pro | AJAX | APIs | Bootstrap | CSS | Express | Firebase | FL Studio | GIMP | GIT | GitHub | Handlebars | Heroku | HTML | JavaScript | JMP | jQuery | Media Queries | Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint) | MongoDB | MySQL | Node | R | React | Responsive Web Design | SAS | VBA | Visual Studio

Language

Intermediate Spanish

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Guitar Scale Book

- Look up musical scales and modes on a virtual fretboard for various instruments, allowing for flexible tuning.
- Utilizes React, Node, JavaScript, and CSS
- Website: https://guitarizard.com

Smart Photo Library

- Store, filter, organize, and automatically tag your photo collection.
- Utilizes React, Node, MongoDB, Materialize, AWS, JavaScript, and CSS
- GitHub: https://github.com/enfenry/Recognicer
- Website: https://mighty-garden-76734.herokuapp.com/

Virtual Planner

- Keep track of your to-do list, budget, and calendar events.
- Utilizes React, Node, MySQL, Material UI, Google OAuth, JavaScript, and CSS
- GitHub: https://github.com/enfenry/Virtual-Planner
- Website: https://blooming-refuge-52964.herokuapp.com/

Sudoku Generator

- Play an infinite amount of Sudoku games at your preferred difficulty level.
- Utilizes React, Node, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and CSS
- GitHub: https://github.com/enfenry/sudoku generator
- Website: https://sudoku-play.herokuapp.com/

EDUCATION

George Washington University, Arlington, VA

• Full Stack Flex Web Development Coding Bootcamp; June 2019

Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University (Virginia Tech), Blacksburg, VA

- **B.S. Psychology**; graduated May 2014
- **B.S. Statistics**; graduated May 2014

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

Trilogy Education Services - September 2019 to current

• Instruct, evaluate, and provide feedback to students in the Full Stack Flex Web Development Coding Bootcamp at George Washington University.

Self-Employed – *July 2018 to current*

• While developing the skills to make a career change, additionally work as a business consultant, musician, and barista.

Senior Pricing Analyst

Halfaker and Associates, LLC. - March 2017 to July 2018

- Analyzed market salary data and developed cost proposals for submission to government agencies, coordinating with Contracts, Operations, Strategy and Growth, and Capture departments.
- Created an adaptive Excel-based pricing model by using Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) in order to run impact analyses of various pricing strategies and contract types (Hybrid, FFP, Cost Plus, and T&M).
- Streamlined the proposal process, reduced team workload, and validated consistency across volumes by programming additional tools.
- Evaluated fairness and realism for subcontractor pricing negotiations.

Pricing Analyst - Sr. Consultant

Booz Allen Hamilton, Inc. - February 2015 to March 2017

- Developed cost proposals for submission to government agencies, coordinating with Contracts and Program Business Support.
- Mitigated financial risk and ensured compliance with FAR, RFP standards, and contract terms by counseling client staff.
- Advised junior analysts to cultivate their knowledge of contract types, Excel cost models, narrative preparation, and setting expectations.
- Managed the pricing team workload balance by assigning proposals and developed smarter Excel-based solutions for tracking analyst bandwidth.

HONORS

Team Shout-Out

• *June 2017* – Recognized for making quick edits on a proposal volume and getting everything done on a very tight deadline with great attention to detail.

High5 Awards

- September 2016 Awarded for working tirelessly, coordinating between the Program Manager, Program Business Services and Contracts to finalize cost proposals.
- September 2015 Awarded in recognition of an outstanding job of completing the Strategic Assessment Contract end of year proposals and helping the Program Manager turn in top quality products to the NASA customer.